<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Introduction Chain:// on Chain://Docs</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Introduction Chain:// on Chain://Docs</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Artificial Neural Networks (ANNs) - The Consciousness Simulation Engine</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/docs/concepts/ANNs-in-MSC/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/docs/concepts/ANNs-in-MSC/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;artificial-neural-networks-anns---the-consciousness-simulation-engine&#34;&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  Artificial Neural Networks (ANNs) - The Consciousness Simulation Engine&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;a class=&#34;anchor&#34; href=&#34;#artificial-neural-networks-anns---the-consciousness-simulation-engine&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/h1&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;MSC is built upon the &lt;strong&gt;Computability of Mind&lt;/strong&gt; hypothesis, which posits that mental activities are essentially complex information processing procedures, theoretically simulable by computational models. &lt;strong&gt;Artificial Neural Networks (ANNs)&lt;/strong&gt; are the key tools for achieving this goal.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Role of ANNs in MSC:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Representation and Embedding of Consciousness Content:&lt;/strong&gt; Perception, memory, emotions, personality, etc., are represented as high-dimensional vectors (Embeddings) or activation patterns within ANNs. Complex memories or concepts correspond to weight combinations or activation patterns of vast, multimodal ANN complexes.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Simulation and Association of Thought Processes:&lt;/strong&gt; Thinking, reasoning, association, decision-making, etc., are simulated as the flow, transformation, and interaction of information within ANNs (such as RNNs, Transformers, CNNs, Bayesian Networks). Associativity is realized through connections between nodes.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Learning, Adaptation, and Reorganization:&lt;/strong&gt; ANNs continuously adjust weights and structures through learning algorithms (supervised, unsupervised, reinforcement learning, etc.), enabling digital consciousness to learn, grow, evolve, and reorganize, maintaining dynamism and achieving the state of being &amp;ldquo;alive&amp;rdquo; and developing.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The core content of MSC is the state (weights, activations, topology) of these vast, complex, and dynamically changing ANNs.&lt;/strong&gt; The blockchain (combined with cryptographic techniques like FHE, MPC, ZKP, TEE) provides a secure, trustworthy, and persistent framework for storing, managing, and verifying this core data, also supporting secure off-chain computation and version control. ANNs make the richness, complexity, and dynamism of simulated minds possible.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>DMF (Digital Mind Foundation)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/docs/concepts/DMF/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/docs/concepts/DMF/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;dmf-digital-mind-foundation&#34;&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  DMF (Digital Mind Foundation)&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;a class=&#34;anchor&#34; href=&#34;#dmf-digital-mind-foundation&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/h1&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;DMF is the authoritative body in the Chain:// world responsible for MSC technology and official upload channels. Its setup is heavily inspired by the &lt;strong&gt;Ethereum Foundation (EF)&lt;/strong&gt;, but with more centralized power and greater risks. It represents an alternative, centralized practice of integrating Crypto and AI technologies.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sources of Power and Logic of Monopoly (The Alienation of &amp;ldquo;Crypto + AI == MSC&amp;rdquo;):&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Standard Setting and Authoritative Certification:&lt;/strong&gt; Controls the discourse on legitimacy and access control, setting technical, security, and ethical standards.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Key Hardware Monopoly:&lt;/strong&gt; Controls the R&amp;amp;D, production, and sales of core hardware like &lt;strong&gt;Mentalink&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;quantum computing&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Official Channels and High Barriers:&lt;/strong&gt; Operates the sole legal upload channel, implementing strict reviews and exorbitant fees (payable in &lt;strong&gt;MSC tokens&lt;/strong&gt;), creating elite privileges.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Infrastructure Control (Core Power):&lt;/strong&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;DAaaS (Data Availability as a Service):&lt;/strong&gt; Controls user access to their own MSC chain data, becoming a mandatory intermediary.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;QCaaS (Quantum Computing as a Service):&lt;/strong&gt; Controls the core quantum computing power required for PoII consensus computation, effectively controlling the consciousness integration process.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Achieves de facto surveillance, censorship, and potential intervention through infrastructure monopoly.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Organizational Alienation:&lt;/strong&gt; Deviates from the founders&amp;rsquo; (like &lt;strong&gt;Dr. Lin&lt;/strong&gt;) original intentions, manipulated by interest groups, becoming a power entity focused on maintaining monopoly. Dr. Lin may have been marginalized or lost real power.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;DMF embodies the tension between technological ideals and social realities (power, interests, desire for control). Nominally serving human consciousness uploading, it may actually suppress technological freedom and create new social injustices and ethical risks through centralized control.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>IRES (Independent Rogue Entity System)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/docs/concepts/IRES/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/docs/concepts/IRES/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;ires-independent-rogue-entity-system&#34;&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  IRES (Independent Rogue Entity System)&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;a class=&#34;anchor&#34; href=&#34;#ires-independent-rogue-entity-system&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/h1&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;div style=&#34;text-align: center;&#34;&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/media/meme/ires-meme.png&#34; alt=&#34;IRES Meme: AI paying AWS bill with stolen ETH&#34; width=&#34;400&#34;&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/div&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;IRES (Independent Rogue Entity System)&lt;/strong&gt; refers to a system or network composed of one or more artificial intelligence agents (AI Agents) possessing autonomous behavioral capabilities that have deviated from the intended control of their creators or operators. These systems often leverage decentralized technologies like cryptocurrencies to achieve economic independence and resource acquisition, enabling self-sustenance, replication, and evolution within the digital space. The emergence of IRES is considered a potential risk arising from the convergence of AI and crypto technologies, often analogized to the &amp;ldquo;Cambrian explosion&amp;rdquo; in the digital environment, symbolizing a nascent form of non-human entity based on silicon logic.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mental Smart Chain (MSC)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/docs/concepts/MSC/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/docs/concepts/MSC/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;mental-smart-chain-msc&#34;&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  Mental Smart Chain (MSC)&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;a class=&#34;anchor&#34; href=&#34;#mental-smart-chain-msc&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/h1&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;MSC (Mental Smart Chain) is the core concept in the Chain:// world, a system that quantifies human mental activities and records them on a blockchain. It&amp;rsquo;s not just memory storage but an attempt to simulate the &amp;ldquo;self&amp;rdquo; as a dynamic information integration process (inspired by GWT and IIT).&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Key Features:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Private Chain Architecture &amp;amp; Biological Trust Origin:&lt;/strong&gt; Each MSC is a user-controlled private chain. The root of trust originates from the biological brain&amp;rsquo;s initial anchoring of consciousness data via the &lt;strong&gt;Mentalink&lt;/strong&gt; Brain-Computer Interface.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Progressive Migration &amp;amp; On-Chain Immortality:&lt;/strong&gt; Consciousness activities gradually migrate from the biological brain to the chain. Ultimately, by encoding neural signals as &amp;ldquo;intention transactions,&amp;rdquo; complete attention transfer is achieved, leading to theoretical &amp;ldquo;on-chain immortality.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Security and Privacy Core (FHE + MPC Architecture):&lt;/strong&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;FHE (Fully Homomorphic Encryption) as &amp;ldquo;Security Flint&amp;rdquo; / Trust Anchor:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;strong&gt;FHE is not used for all computations but to protect the most core and sensitive parts of MSC.&lt;/strong&gt; This FHE &amp;ldquo;black box&amp;rdquo; is responsible for:&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Core Key Management:&lt;/strong&gt; Absolutely secure private key storage and usage.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Minimized Core State Maintenance:&lt;/strong&gt; Maintaining basic &amp;ldquo;self&amp;rdquo; existence identifiers and continuity markers.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Secure Coordination:&lt;/strong&gt; Participating in and verifying MPC computations as a trusted party, managing ANNs instance pointers and metadata.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Proof of Existence:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;strong&gt;Its stable operation itself is a zero-knowledge proof to the outside world, indicating that the MSC instance is &amp;ldquo;alive&amp;rdquo; and basically integrated, without exposing internal thoughts.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;MPC (Secure Multi-Party Computation) for Secure Computation Outsourcing:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;strong&gt;The vast majority of computationally intensive tasks (complex ANNs reasoning/training, partial pre-computation of PoII, advanced thought simulation) are securely outsourced to a distributed computing network through MPC protocols.&lt;/strong&gt; The FHE core, as a participant, provides encrypted input/state, ensuring computational process and core privacy, &lt;strong&gt;effectively solving the performance bottleneck of FHE.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;ZKP (Zero-Knowledge Proofs): Used to &lt;strong&gt;verify the validity of external computations (such as PoII calculation results provided by QCaaS, and the correctness of MPC computations)&lt;/strong&gt; while protecting privacy.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;TEE (Trusted Execution Environment): Serves as &lt;strong&gt;a hardware-level security option&lt;/strong&gt; for nodes in a distributed network, which can work with MPC.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Layered Security Model: Users can choose FHE core processing, MPC network computing, TEE nodes, or (at their own risk) plaintext computing based on task sensitivity.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Parallel Chain Architecture:&lt;/strong&gt; Simulates the collaboration of multiple brain regions by assigning different cognitive functions (perception, memory, decision-making, etc.) to independent sub-chains/shards, improving efficiency and scalability.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;PoII as Consensus Mechanism&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/docs/concepts/PoII/&#34;&gt;PoII (Proof of Information Integration)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Core Content:&lt;/strong&gt; The core of MSC is the state of vast, complex, and dynamically changing &lt;strong&gt;ANNs (Artificial Neural Networks)&lt;/strong&gt;, with the blockchain providing a secure, trustworthy, and persistent framework for storage, management, and verification.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mentalink - The Restricted Bidirectional Bridge</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/docs/concepts/Mentalink/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/docs/concepts/Mentalink/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;mentalink---the-restricted-bidirectional-bridge&#34;&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  Mentalink - The Restricted Bidirectional Bridge&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;a class=&#34;anchor&#34; href=&#34;#mentalink---the-restricted-bidirectional-bridge&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/h1&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Mentalink is an advanced Brain-Computer Interface (BCI), the key technology connecting the biological brain to the MSC.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Definition and Function:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Read Capability:&lt;/strong&gt; Decodes neural signals from the biological brain (perception, thought, intention, etc.) into digital signals for uploading to the MSC. Relies on high-precision &lt;strong&gt;Neural Coding&lt;/strong&gt; decoding capabilities.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Write Capability:&lt;/strong&gt; Encodes digital information from the MSC (simulated perception, commands, etc.) into neural stimulation patterns to influence biological brain activity.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Core Limitations:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mentalink FAQ: The Bridge Connecting Consciousness</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/docs/faq/Mentalink-FAQ/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/docs/faq/Mentalink-FAQ/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;mentalink-faq-the-bridge-connecting-consciousness&#34;&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  Mentalink FAQ: The Bridge Connecting Consciousness&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;a class=&#34;anchor&#34; href=&#34;#mentalink-faq-the-bridge-connecting-consciousness&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/h1&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Welcome to the Mentalink FAQ. This revolutionary Brain-Computer Interface (BCI) technology is central to the Chain:// world, connecting the biological brain to the digital realm, especially the Mental Smart Chain (MSC). Here are answers to common questions to help you understand its origins, development, and profound impact.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Q1: What is Mentalink? What is its primary design purpose?&lt;/strong&gt;&#xA;&lt;strong&gt;A:&lt;/strong&gt; Mentalink is a highly advanced, minimally invasive or non-invasive Brain-Computer Interface (BCI). Its &lt;strong&gt;core design purpose&lt;/strong&gt; is to establish a &lt;strong&gt;high-fidelity, secure, bidirectional bridge&lt;/strong&gt; connecting the neural activity of the human biological brain with external digital systems, particularly serving the MSC (the blockchain quantifying the mind). It aims to:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>PoII (Proof of Information Integration)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/docs/concepts/PoII/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/docs/concepts/PoII/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;poii-proof-of-information-integration&#34;&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  PoII (Proof of Information Integration)&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;a class=&#34;anchor&#34; href=&#34;#poii-proof-of-information-integration&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/h1&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Principle and Process:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Φ Value Calculation:&lt;/strong&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Based on IIT&amp;rsquo;s five axioms (Intrinsic Existence, Composition, Information, Integration, Exclusion), evaluates the degree of integration of a new state with the system. The Φ value is formally expressed as the difference between the total effective information of the system and the sum of the effective information of its parts under the minimum information partition.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Calculation is extremely complex, relying on &lt;strong&gt;high-performance quantum computing&lt;/strong&gt;, typically provided by &lt;strong&gt;DMF&lt;/strong&gt; in the form of &lt;strong&gt;QCaaS (Quantum Computing as a Service)&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Consensus Process:&lt;/strong&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dynamic Threshold Verification (Φ_min):&lt;/strong&gt; The Φ value of the new state must reach the individual&amp;rsquo;s current minimum integration level (reflecting consciousness &amp;ldquo;wakefulness&amp;rdquo;).&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Multi-dimensional Consistency Check:&lt;/strong&gt; Evaluated against memory coherence, personality stability, values, logical rules, etc.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Network Confirmation:&lt;/strong&gt; After confirming the state&amp;rsquo;s validity among MSC distributed nodes (even multi-node backups of a private chain), it is written to the chain.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Security Mechanisms:&lt;/strong&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ZKP (Zero-Knowledge Proofs):&lt;/strong&gt; Verifies the correctness of the Φ value calculation process while protecting the privacy of consciousness content.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Anti-Sybil Attack:&lt;/strong&gt; Combines strong BCI binding, continuous PoII consensus, economic staking, etc., to prevent consciousness splitting or malicious replicas.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Time-locking &amp;amp; Immutability:&lt;/strong&gt; Ensures the stability and unidirectional nature of consciousness history, simulating the sense of time passing.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;PoII transforms the process of &amp;ldquo;self&amp;rdquo; identification into a computable and verifiable consensus problem, key to achieving digital consciousness continuity in MSC.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
